# Che Bajandas – Senior Quality Assurance Engineer – San Francisco, California

chebajandas@gmail.com - 510-333-1813 - linkedin.com/in/che-bajandas/

Well-rounded quality assurance engineer or analyst with a specialization in software and background in web and mobile based applications. 11 years of experience in software quality assurance with 5 years of experience working on an online web-based video game and 6 years of experience working on a mobile job searching application. Expertise in front-end verification, regression testing, release management, test planning, and leadership.

### Skills and Abilities

Embedded quality assurance | Release management | Test planning | Test casing | Production monitoring | Interfacing with customer support | Cross team collaboration | Agile methodologies | UI/UX and technical design review | SDLC: Software Development Lifecycle | CI/CD: Continuous Integration/Continuous Deployment | Software quality assurance methodologies and best practices | Automation strategy | Mobile apps | Web apps | APIs | "Shift Left" methodologies | Debugging | Troubleshooting | Root cause analysis | Regression testing | Verification

# **Technologies**

JIRA, Confluence | Google Suite: Google Docs, Google Sheets, etc. | GitLab, Git, SVN | Jenkins, GitLab CI | TestRail, PractiTest, Zephyr | Xcode, Android Studio | iOS simulators, Android emulators | App Store Connect, Google Play Console | SQL, JavaScript, Java, Python | Selenium, Appium | Web inspection, cookies, network traffic | Charles Web Proxy | Sauce Labs, BrowserStack | Mac, Windows, iOS, and Android operating systems

## Experience

## Senior Quality Assurance Manager - Indeed

05/2017 - 03/2023

Team lead, key decision maker, and direct manager of engineers across disciplines and functional teams.

- Managed quality assurance engineers and automation engineers from junior up to technical fellow.
- Established verification and regression testing process for the mobile apps product from the ground up, reducing QA turn-around time for a new app version from months to days.
- Rapidly and effectively built-up knowledge of mobile app development and release and testing processes.
- Oversaw company mandated improvements to release velocity and successfully increased the frequency of app releases from once every 1-2 months to once every week for both iOS and Android.
- Worked side by side with senior automation engineer to establish testing strategy and establish automated testing, bringing coverage up from 0% to 70% of frontend regression test cases.
- Expanded knowledge across teams working with the frontend and backend for web applications as well as the frontend and backend supporting mobile applications, including API testing.
- Collaborated cross team and cross functionally on a daily basis; worked alongside leads to establish product team goals and track progress towards them.

#### Quality Assurance Lead – KIXEYE

08/2012 - 05/2017

Team lead, key decision maker, and direct manager of engineers for the flagship product in a high-pressure environment.

- Rapidly and effectively built-up knowledge of software development and quality assurance practices.
- Took on increased responsibility of the team and made significant changes to processes, increasing efficiency and velocity, allowing for less overtime for team members.
- Essential contributor towards team success in meeting key objectives and company revenue goals through direct oversight of product deliverables.

### Education

San Francisco State University

Bachelor of the Arts (BA) in English Literature

2006 – 2010

# **Trainings and Certifications**

- · Technical privacy training
- · Managing and the law
- Crucial Conversations
- Workplace harassment training with manager focus
- Various formal interview trainings

#### **Awards**

Unicorn Award - KIXEYE - 2016

Awarded by peers in popular vote for outstanding performance and outsized contributions.

#### **Endorsements**

"Che is such a multi-talented and deeply skilled manager that it's hard to even know where to begin to describe him. He managed QA for my team, and I've never seen it done better: small and tight releases shipped regularly, close monitoring of production, and detailed quality metrics read out to the whole team every week. Across QA, Eng, and UX functions, Che applies a masterful sense of operations, always in the forefront of identifying process gaps and closing them. The continual improvement that he drove in our whole group made us better and better and better over time. The incremental improvement in a whole year was sometimes staggering. But more than that, I trust Che. I'm the Product lead for our group and always knew I could tap Che for an important decision or to lead an important initiative."

- Andy Hilal, Senior Product Manager, Indeed

"What can I say about Che. He is one of the best managers I have ever worked with. I worked with him for over 4 years and 3 years reporting to him. He has unparalleled attention to detail and has always been someone with the highest level of integrity and fairness. No matter the complexity you can always expect him to deliver."

- Jinesh Doshi, Quality Assurance Automation Fellow, Indeed

"His ability to communicate complex ideas into very digestible concepts is second to none... he has setup the foundation of QA for Indeed's mobile app infrastructure, has grown the careers of our QA engineers and QA automation engineers, introduced new technology to advance our tools, and has led numerous org wide initiatives around compliance, delivery lead time, and accessibility. I could not ask for a better QA counterpart to work together with our engineering team on streamlining our delivery process, identifying process optimizations, and being a trustworthy friend and colleague."

- Chris Barretto, Senior Software Engineering Manager, Indeed

"Che was one of the best managers I've ever had. He identified opportunities for me to expand my experience and skills, which led me to become the QA lead for our team. I've always felt comfortable sharing my professional

challenges with him and his meaningful feedback provided me with clarity on my next steps. I'm confident that Che will be a great asset to the next team he'll manage."

- Yvette Tran, Quality Assurance Engineer II, Indeed

"When I think of Che, the first word that comes to mind is dedication. Whether it was his team, his work, or the product, Che was always dedicated to making sure everything was a success. No matter where he goes, you can expect him to deliver."

- Joshua Groezinger, Quality Assurance Automation Engineer II, Indeed

Visit <u>linkedin.com/in/che-bajandas/</u> for full quotes and details under the recommendations section.